Guide to the Horace Davis Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Horace Davis Papers
1865-1916
SC0028
Davis, Horace, 1831-1916
3 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Mrs. George Proctor.
Information about Access
None.
Biography
Horace Davis was a United States representative from California, a member of the original Board of Trustees of Stanford University (1885-1916), and President of the University of California.
Scope and Content
Papers include family correspondence (with a few pertaining to the Civil War United States Sanitary Commission); correspondence relating to the administration of Stanford University; and a few articles by Davis, diplomas, and pamphlets. The bulk of the papers concern Stanford University, its Board of Trustees, and the problems it faced such as salaries, tuition and fees, faculty reirements, discipline, the 1906 arthquake, and problems of organizing the Board of Trustees. Correspondents include Thomas R. Bard, George Crothers, Henry T. Gage, David Starr Jordan, Samuel F. Leib, George C. Perkins, James D. Phelan, Whitelaw Reid, Eugene E. Schmitz, Silas W. Terry, Booker T. Washington, Benjamin Ide Wheeler and John D. Works.
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, 1865-1916
  - 1865-1867 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 2)
    - 83 ALS and TLS to Davis from: L.B. Farnum; F.W. Vaughan; Alex McDonald; William A. Everett; Eliza Davis (letters are signed E.D. or Mother); George Bancroft; Alex S. Taylor; Alice Dow; John G. [Dawes]; John Charles Bancroft Davis; N.A.M.; Andrew Davis; H.L. [Breed]; Edward Blunt(?); Frederica G. Davis; James Otis; George N. Minot; Hasbrouck; William R. Wadsworth; John Currey (on same letter, signatures of Tom Sweet, M.C. Blanke, Saml. Cowler, H.J. Tilden and L.J. Henry); Horatio R. Storer; and J.W. Austin. (Filed in the order named).
    - 17 ALS from Horace Davis to Lavinia M. Davis, Eliza Davis and John Charles Bancroft Davis.
    - 1 n.d. from H. Stibbins.
    - 4 Visitors' Tickets to: Merchants Exchange and News Room; Chicago Board of Trade; Union Merchants' Exchange; and Golden Gate Flouring Mill.
    - Davis' own index to the above letters arranged in alphabetical order.
  - 1897-1899 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - TLS from John D. Long, 1897 24 Mar
    - TLS from Geo[rge] F. Hoar and TLS from James D. Phelan (also signed by the Commander of the Calif. Commandery and President of the Sons of the American Revolution, John C. -----), 1899 9 Jan
    - ALS from W.J. Rolphe, 1899 12 Jan
    - ALS from Chester Rowell, 1899 13 Jan
    - TLS from Geo[rge] C. Perkins, 1899 8 Feb
    - ALS from Kendric Charles Babcock, 13 Feb 1899
    - ALS from Silas W. Terry, 8 Mar 1899
    - ALS from [Henry Glass], 9 Mar 1899
    - ALS from Geo. C. Perkins, 14 Apr 1899
    - ALS from Martin Kellogg, 19 Apr 1899
    - ALS from Silas W. Terry, 21 Apr 1899
    - TLS from John D. Works, 10 May 1899
    - ALS from Jane Stanford, 29 May 1899
    - TLS from Henry T. Gage, 27 Aug 1899
    - TLS from Irving M. Scott, 15 Sep 1899
    - ALS from [Wm.] Phelan, 21 Sep 1899
    - TLS from Edwin D. Mead, 23 Sep 1899
    - TLS from John D. Long, 27 Sep 1899
    - ALS from N.P. Gilman, 14 Oct 1899
    - TLS from Benj[amin] Ide Wheeler, 18 Oct 1899
    - TLS from Henry T. Gage, 22 Nov 1899
  - 1900-1902 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - TLS from Benj. Ide Wheeler; David Starr Jordan; Thomas J. Kirk, 25-Jan-00
    - TLS from Edward E. Hale (also, an ALS without date), 1-Feb-00
    - TLS from Thomas R. Bard, 19-Feb-00
    - TLS from Benj. Ide Wheeler, 31-Mar-00
    - TLS from Edward E. Hale, 7 May 1900
    - TLS from ?, 26 May 1900
    - TLS from Benj. Ide Wheeler, 8-Sep-00
    - TLS from John D. Works; Wm. H. Knight; Kathryne J. Wilson, 26-Sep-00
    - TLS from Thomas R. Bard, 12-Nov-00
    - TLS from F. S. Stratton, 30-Nov-00
    - TLS from Ralph C. Harrison, 20-Mar-01
    - ALS from John D. Long; Edw[ard] E. Hale., 18 May 1901
    - TLS from James D. Phelan, 20 May 1901
    - TLS from Carroll D. Wright, 5-Aug-01
    - TLS from James D. Phelan, 19-Aug-01
    - TLS from John Barrett, 9-Oct-01
    - ALS from Henry Glass, 28-Nov-01
    - TLS from E.E. Schmitz, 26-Dec-01
    - TLS from Benj. Ide Wheeler, 22-Jan-02
    - TLS from Henry Glass, 27-Jan-02
    - TLS from E.E. Schmitz, 31-Jan-02
    - ALS from Worthington C. Ford, 3-Feb-02
    - TLS from [Judge's Chambers, San Francisco.], 26-Feb-02
    - TLS from Geo. C. Perkins, 8-Mar-02
    - TLS from Geo. C. Perkins, 19-Mar-02
    - TLS from E.E. Schmitz, 29 May 1902
    - TLS from E.E. Schmitz, 4 June 1902
    - TLS from Geo. C. Perkins, 15 July 1902
    - TLS from Geo. C. Perkins, 23 July 1902
    - TLS from Benj. Ide Wheeler, 23-Aug-02
    - TLS from Benj. Ide Wheeler, 28-Aug-02
    - TLS from Benj. Ide Wheeler, 30-Aug-02
  - 1903 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - TLS from [Wm. M. Morris], 15-Jan-03
    - TLS from Booker T. Washington, 21-Feb-03
    - TLS from Geo. C. Perkins, 27-Feb-03
    - TLS from Vernon L. Kellogg, 15-Apr-03
    - Carbon to the Board of Trustees from Jane L. Stanford, 1 June 1903
    - TL from no sig., 3-Aug-03
    - TLS from Charles N. Eliot, 29-Sep-03
    - TLS from Benj. Ide Wheeler, 20-Aug-03
    - TL from no sig., 1-Sep-03
    - ALS from Francis W. Kelsey, 4-Sep-03
    - TLS from David S. Jordan, 9-Sep-03
    - TLS from J.P. Harrin (with enclosed pamphlet on the Professional Pension Fund), 11-Sep-03
    - TLS from J.G. Schurman, 24-Sep-03
    - TLS from J.G. Schurman, 10-Oct-03
    - TLS from Arthur T. Hadley, 11-Sep-03
    - TLS from Whitelaw Reid to Charles G. Lathrop, 16-Sep-03
    - TLS from Charles G. Lathrop to Geo. E. Crothers, 21-Sep-03
    - TLS from Lathrop to Reid, 21-Sep-03
    - TLS from Arthur T. Hadley, 7-Oct-03
    - TLS from David S. Jordan, 11-Sep-03
    - TLS from S.F. Leib, 22-Sep-03
    - TLS from S.F. Leib, 6-Nov-03
    - AL from no sig., 3-Dec-03
    - TLS from James B. Angell with pamphlet on laws and by-laws of the U. of Michigan, 16-Sep-03
    - TLS from Jordan, 19-Sep-03
    - TLS from Jordan, 22-Sep-03
    - TLS from Benj. Ide Wheeler, 25-Sep-03
    - TLS from Cyrus Northrup, 6-Oct-03
    - TLS from Wheeler, 8-Oct-03
    - TLS from Whitelaw Reid, 15-Oct-03
    - TLS from Reid with enclosure re Columbia U., 17-Oct-03
    - TLS from [Nicholas M. Butler], 19-Oct-03
    - ALS from Booker T. Washington, 7-Nov-03
    - TLS from [Butler], 9-Nov-03
    - TLS from Wheeler, 4-Dec-03
    - TLS from John W. Foster; Thomas Nelson Page., 10-Dec-03
    - Carbon from Jordan to Jacob Gould Schurman, 14-Dec-03
    - Carbon from Jordan, 15-Dec-03
    - Carbon from Jordan, 16-Dec-03
    - TLS from O.L. Elliott, 16-Dec-03
    - Carbon from Jordan, 17-Dec-03
    - ALS from John Maxson Stillman, 17-Dec-03
    - Carbon from Jordan, 18-Dec-03
    - Carbon from Jordan, 18-Dec-03
    - Carbon from Jordan, 19-Dec-03
    - ALS from O.L. Elliott, 20-Dec-03
    - TLS from John W. Foster, 28-Dec-03
  - 1904 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - ALS from H. Rushton Fairclough, 24-Jan-04
    - TLS from Wheeler, 25-Jan-04
    - Carbon from Jordan, 28-Jan-04
    - Carbon from Ewald Flugel to Jordan, 28-Jan-04
    - ALS from Max Farrand, 1-Feb-04
    - TLS from Geo. E. Crothers to Farran, 5-Feb-04
    - Carbon from Jordan, 2-Feb-04
    - TLS from Geo. E. Crothers, 3-Feb-04
    - Carbon from Jordan with enclosed data sheet, 5-Feb-04
    - TLS from Farrand to Crothers, 10-Feb-04
    - TL to John M. Stillman, 16-Feb-04
    - TLS from O.L. Elliott, 18-Dec-04
    - TLS from J.M. Stillman, 20-Feb-04
    - ALS from Chas. D---, 20-Feb-04
    - TLS from Max Farrand, 19-Feb-04
    - ALS from Stillman, 21-Feb-04
    - Carbon from Davis to Stillman, 7-Mar-04
    - ALS from Stillman, 3-Mar-04
    - ALS from Stillman, 15-Mar-04
    - ALS from Davis to Stillman, 16-Mar-04
    - Carbon from Stillman, 17-Mar-04
    - Carbon from Jordan, 18-Mar-04
    - Carbon from Jordan, 19-Mar-04
    - TLS from Stillman, 21-Mar-04
    - TLS from [Ira W. Hollis], 25-Mar-04
    - ALS from Charles W. Eliot, 1-Apr-04
    - Carbon from Jordan, 5-Apr-04
    - Carbon from Chas. G. Lathrop to S.F. Leib, 14-Apr-04
    - Carbon from Jordan, 18-Apr-04
    - Carbon from Jordan with salary roll, 18-Apr-04
    - Carbon from Jordan, 18-Apr-04
    - Carbon from Jordan, 25-Apr-04
    - Carbon from Jordan (2), 26-Apr-04
    - Carbon from Jordan, 5 May 1904
    - Carbon from Jordan with enclosure, 23 May 1904
    - ALS from Albert A. [Harvard]?, 12 June 1904
    - ALS from H. Morse Stephens, 13 July 1904
    - TLS from Wm. M. Stewart, 24-Aug-04
    - TLS from Geo. E. Crothers to James Hogg, 23-Sep-04
    - Carbon from Jordan, 4-Oct-04
    - ALS from Crothers, 8-Oct-04
    - ALS from Geo. [George E. Crothers], 8-Oct-04
    - Carbon from Jordan, 10-Oct-04
    - TL from Jordan to S.F. Leib, 25-Oct-04
    - TLS from Crothers, 10-Nov-04
    - TLS from Crothers to Mrs. Stanford, 24-Oct-04
    - TLS from Crothers, 22-Nov-04
    - TLS from Crothers, 25-Nov-04
    - TLS from Crothers to C.M. Gayley, 31-Dec-04
  - 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - The Barnett Case, 1905 -
      - Carbon from Jordan to Prof. S.J. Barnett, 16-Dec-04
      - Carbon from P.G. Nutting to Barnett, 27-Mar-05
      - Carbon from Barnett to Jordan, 4, 16, 25 Feb 1905
      - Carbon from Barnett to Jordan, 29-Mar-05
      - Carbon from Barnett to Jordan, 4-Apr-05
      - Carbon from Barnett to Jordan, 8-Apr-05
      - Carbon from Barnett to Jordan, 4 May 1905
      - Carbon from Jordan to Barnett, 4 May 1905
      - Carbon from Jordan to Barnett, 19 May 1905
      - Carbon from Barnett to Fernando Sanford, 20 May 1905
      - Carbon from Barnett to Jordan, 22 May 1905
      - Carbon from Jordan to Barnett, 24 May 1905
      - TLS from Barnett to the Board of Trustees, 31 July 1905
    - The Carl C. Rice Case, 1905 -
      - Carbon from Jordan to Rice, 28-Feb-05
      - Carbon from Rice to Jordan, 22-Mar-05
      - Carbon from Jordan to Rice, 25-Mar-05
      - ALS from Rice to Davis, 8-Apr-05
      - ALS from Rice to Davis, 9-Apr-05
    - TLS from Crothers, 5-Jan-05
    - TLS from Crothers, 16-Jan-05
    - Carbon from Mrs. Stanford to the Board of Trustees, 1-Feb-05
    - TLS from Crothers to Lathrop, Davis and Jordan, 6-Feb-05; (3 letters)
    - TLS from Crothers to Jordan, 24-Feb-05
    - 2 telegrams re death of Mrs. Stanford, Mar 1905
    - Holograph note by Davis re Mrs. Stanford, undated
    - ALS from Crothers, 10-Mar-05
    - TLS from Crothers, 25-Mar-05
    - TLS from Crothers to Whitelaw Reid, 27-Mar-05
    - TLS from Crothers to Jordan, 30-Mar-05
    - TLS from Crothers to Jordan, 1-Apr-05
    - ALS from manager of the Hotel Metropole in London, 24-Apr-05
    - TL circular to members of the faculty, 15-Apr-05
    - TLS from Crothers, 20-Apr-05
    - TL no sig., 2 May 1905
    - Carbon from Jordan, 3 May 1905
    - TL from Crothers, 6 May 1905
    - TL no sig. to Jordan, 20 May 1905
    - Carbon from Thomas W. Stanford to Crothers, 26 May 1905
    - ALS from G. Crothers, 26 May 1905
    - TLS from Crothers, 29 May 1905
    - TLS from Crothers, 30 May 1905
    - ALS from Jordan, 1 June 1905
    - Carbon from Jordan to Crothers, 1 June 1905
    - ALS from Jordan, 3 June 1905
    - TLS from Crothers, 9 June 1905
    - TLS from Geo. Crothers, 23 June 1905
    - ALS from Crothers, 2-Sep-05
    - TL no sig. to Jordan, 10-Oct-05
    - Carbon from Jordan to Crothers, 11-Oct-05
    - TLS from Crothers, 18-Oct-05
    - Carbon from Henry A. Schulze to Charles E. Hodges, 26-Oct-05
    - Carbon from Crothers to Jordan, 27-Oct-05
    - Carbon from Crothers to Charles B. Wing, 30-Oct-05
    - Carbon from Crothers to Messrs. Edwin Duruea, Jr. and Henry A. Schulze, 30-Oct-05
    - Carbon from [Crothers] to Schulze, 31-Oct-05
    - ALS from Crothers, 2-Dec-05
    - ALS from Whitelaw Reid, 13-Mar-06
    - TLS from Wm. James, 19-Apr-06
    - (5) TLS from Jordan, 20, 21, 26 May and 5, 7 June 1906
  - 1907-1908 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Carbon from Meyers and Ward to Leon Sloss, 1-Feb-07
    - Carbon from Lathrop to Chas. D. Marx, 4-Feb-07
    - TLS from Crothers, 18-Apr-07
    - Carbon from George T. Clark to the Board of Trustees, 3-Aug-07
    - TLS from Timothy Hopkins, 14-Aug-07
    - TLS from Timothy Hopkins, 16-Aug-07
    - Carbon from Charles P. Eells, 17-Aug-07
    - Carbon from G.T. Clark to the President's office [Jordan], 15-Aug-07
    - Carbon from Jordan, 6-Sep-07
    - Carbon from Jordan to Crothers, 16-Sep-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Jordan, 17-Sep-07
    - Carbon from Chas. D. Marx to Crother, 21-Sep-07
    - Carbon from Jordan, 26-Sep-07
    - TLS from Wilson and Wilson, 4-Oct-07
    - typed receipt signed by Davis, 4-Oct-07
    - Carbon from Jordan to Crothers, 7-Oct-07
    - TLS from Ernest N. Smith, 10-Oct-07
    - holograph note marked private for Ernest N. Smith, undated
    - TLS from Ernest N. Smith, 20-Oct-07
    - [holograph] motes on budget, undated
    - TLS from Wm. Channing Brown to the Life Members of the American Unitarian Association, 3-Apr-08
    - TLS from Crothers, 17-Apr-08
    - TLS from Grace T. Gay, 4 May 1908
    - Carbon from Jordan, 5 May 1908
    - TL from D. Charles Gardner to the Board of Trustees, 17 May 1908
    - TL from Crothers to Percy F. Valentine, 22 May 1908
    - TLS from Crothers, 22 May 1908
    - Mailing list for Some Radical Needs at Stanford. Initialed by Crothers, 22 July 1908
    - TLS from C.A. Duniway, 24 July 1908
    - TLS from Geo. J. Bancroft, 18-Aug-08
    - ALS from Crothers, 1-Sep-08
    - TLS from James B. Angell, 16-Sep-08
    - TLS from Ellwood P. Cubberley, 17-Sep-08
    - Carbon from Jordan, 23-Sep-08
    - TLS from Crothers, 21 July 1908
    - TLS from Crothers to G.T. Clark, 27 July 1908
    - TLS from Crothers to Stillman, 27 July 1908
    - Telegram from Stillman to E.D. Adan, 28 July 1908
    - Carbon from Crothers to Lathrop, 4-Aug-08
    - Carbon from Crothers to Noble Electric Company, 4-Sep-08
    - TLS from Lathrop, 7-Sep-08
    - Carbon from Jordan to Lathrop, 7-Sep-08
    - TLS from Lathrop to Jordan, 7-Sep-08
    - Carbon from Jordan to Lathrop, 8-Sep-08
    - TL from Jordan to Lester S. Walbridge, 9-Sep-08
    - Carbon from Jordan, 9-Sep-08
    - Carbon from Jordan, 10-Sep-08
    - ALS from Henry [W.] Elliott to the Board of Trustees, 29-Sep-08
    - ALS from Henry W. Elliott to G.W. Clark, 29-Sep-08
    - Carbon from Jordan to the Board of Trustees, 1-Oct-08
    - Carbon from Branner to Jordan, 1-Oct-08
    - TLS from James E. Montgomery with an extract from the Indianapolis Star of Sep. 27, 1-Oct-08
    - Carbon from Montgomery to Jordan, 1-Oct-08
    - Carbon from Crothers to Elmer A. Breckenfeld, 3-Oct-08
    - Carbon from Terry W. Ward to Crothen, 9-Oct-08
    - Carbon from Crothers to Ward, 12-Oct-08
    - Carbon from Frederic C. Woodward to Crothers, 28-Oct-08
    - Carbon from Crothers to Woodward, 6-Nov-08
    - TLS from S.F. Leib, 23-Nov-08
  - 1910-1916 and undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - TLS from Timothy Hopkins with rough sketch of a library lot [in San Francisco], 1 June 1910
    - TLS from Lathrop with statement of professors' salaries and their number of students, 4 June 1910
    - Telegram from Phoebe A. Hurst, 19-Sep-14
    - Holograph postcard from [A.A.S.]?, 26 June 1916
    - TLS from W. Mayo Newhall to Norris Davis, 10-Aug-16
    - ALS from Crothers, undated
    - ALS from Crothers to members of the Organization Committee of the Board of Trustees, undated
    - ALS from C. Gayley, 27 Jan
    - ALS from Franklin K. Lane, 6 Feb
    - ALS from S.F. Leib, 2 Oct 190-
    - ALS from Jane Stanford, undated
- Julius Goebel case, 1904-1908
  - Correspondence, 1904-1905 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Carbon from Julius Goebel to Mrs. Stanford, 6 June 1904
    - Goebel to Jordan, 20-Feb-05
    - Crothers to S.F. Leib, 23-Feb-05
    - Melvin G. Dodge to Stillman, 6-Mar-05
    - Stillman to Jordan, 18-Mar-05
    - Jordan to the Board of Trustees, 25-Mar-05
    - Dodge to Jordan, 28-Mar-05
    - Jordan to Crothers, 31-Mar-05
    - Two pages holograph notes re Goebel affair, 26-Apr-05
    - A.T. Murray to Jordan, 28-Apr-05
    - Jordan to the Board of Trustees, 15 May 1905
    - Goebel to the sec. of the Board of Trustees, 17 May 1905
    - Goebel to Jordan, 24 May 1905
    - Jordan to Goebel, 24 May 1905
    - Goebel to Jordan, 24 May 1905
    - Goebel to the sec. of the Board of Trustees, 24 May 1905
    - Jordan to Goebel, 25 May 1905
    - J.C. Branner to the Board of Trustees, 31 May 1905
    - 33 citizens of San Jose to the sec. of the Board of Trustees, undated
    - 25 citizens of San Francisco to ---, undated
    - Goebel to the Board of Trustees, 7 July 1905
    - Crothers to Branner, 17 July 1905
    - C.J. Hexamer to the Board of Trustee, 17 July 1905
    - Martin Singer to Davis with a copy of an article on Autocracy in an American University - The Cause of the Stanford Troubles., 17 July 1905
    - Branner to Crothers, 18 July 1905
    - no sig. to S.F. Leib, 18 July 1905
    - no sig. to S.F. Leib, 19 July 1905
    - Singer to Davis, 22 July 1905
    - no sig. to S.F. Leib, 28 July 1905
    - Jordan to Theodore Roosevelt with a copy of Goebel's statement (in German) on Roosevelt's book The Winning of the West, and copies of several newspaper clippings re the matter, 28-Feb-05
    - Jordan to the Board of Trustees, 25-Mar-05
    - Crothers to Jordan, 1-Apr-05
    - A.T. Murray to Jordan, 19-Apr-05
    - Goebel to the Advisory Board of the Academic Council, 24-Apr-05
    - Jordan to the Advisory Board of the Academic Council, 26-Apr-05
    - Jordan to the Board of Trustees, 15 May 1905
    - Jordan to the Board of Trustees, 15 May 1905
    - Jordan to Goebel, 25 May 1905
    - Martin Singer to Thomas W. Stanford, 18 July 1905
    - Extract from a letter of Dr. Branner, 18 July 1905
    - Crothers to Leib, 28 July 1905
    - Joseph Hutchinson to Davis, 31 July 1905
    - Resolution from the Board of Trustee, 3-Aug-05
    - Goebel to the Board of Trustees, 5-Aug-05
    - Martin Singer to the Board of Trustees, 10-Aug-05
    - C. Schulz to Crothers, 12-Aug-05
    - Herbert Weir Smyth to Goebel, 27-Aug-05
    - ALS from Goebel to Davis, 6-Sep-05
    - [Davis] to Branner, 11-Sep-05
    - TLS from Charles N. Eliot, 14-Sep-05
    - TLS from Charles N. Eliot, 7-Oct-05
    - TLS from Charles N. Eliot, 30-Oct-05
    - TLS from Charles N. Eliot, 25-Nov-05
    - Jordan to Davis, 12-Sep-05
    - Davis to Jordan, 13-Sep-05
    - Jordan to Davis, 14-Sep-05
    - no sig. to T.W. Stanford, 21-Sep-05
    - TLS from Crothers, 23-Sep-05
    - Memo from Board of Trustees to Crothers, 26-Sep-05
    - Memo from Jordan to the Board of Trustees, 28-Sep-05
    - TLS from Crothers, 3-Oct-05
    - Goebel to William Denman, 18-Oct-05
    - TLS from Denman to Davis, 23-Oct-05
    - Jordan to Davis, 6-Nov-05
    - G.A. Clark to Jordan, 6-Nov-05
    - Crothers to Davis, 6-Nov-05
  - Correspondence, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - TLS from Crothers with enclosure, 5-Jan-06
    - ALS from Goebel, 22-Jan-06
    - TLS from Karl G. Rendtorff, 5-Feb-06
    - TLS from Denman, 6-Feb-06
    - Carbon from Jordan, 12-Feb-06
    - ALS from Goebel, 2-Mar-06
    - Carbon from Geo. V. Skal to Rendtorf, 16-Mar-06
    - TLS from Rendtorff, 24-Mar-06
    - ALS from [Denman] with 15 enclosures, 16-Apr-06
  - Correspondence, 1907-1908 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - h. carbon from Nathan Abbott, 5 May 1907
    - h. carbon from Stillman to E[dwin] J. James, 7 May 1907
    - AL no sig., 22 June 1907
    - TLS from Denman, 24 June 1907
    - ALS from Crothers, 28 June 1907
    - TLS from Denman, 28 June 1907
    - h. carbon from Goebel, 29 June 1907
    - TLS from Edwin J. James, 1 July 1907
    - TLS from [Davis] to James, 1 July 1907
    - AL from [Davis] to James, 8 July 1907
    - TL from [Davis] to James, 8 July 1907
    - TLS from Denman, 8 July 1907
    - TLS from Crothers, 8 July 1907
    - ALS from Crothers, 9 July 1907
    - Carbon from Crothers to Goebel, 15 July 1907
    - Carbon from Crothers with enclosure of Correspondence between Goebel and Jordan (1 Goebel to G.A. Clark), all carbons, all 1905:, 16 July 1907
      - Jordan to Goebel, 28-Feb-05
      - Jordan to Goebel, 25-Mar-05
      - Goebel to G.A. Clark, 28-Mar-05
      - Jordan to Goebel, 6-Apr-05
      - Goebel to Jordan, 12-Apr-05
      - Jordan to Goebel, 15-Apr-05
      - Goebel to Jordan, 16-Apr-05
      - Jordan to Goebel, 17-Apr-05
      - Goebel to Jordan, 18-Apr-05
      - Goebel to Jordan, 22-Apr-05
    - ALS from Goebel, 25 July 1907
    - ALS from Charles P. Eells, 3-Aug-07
    - ALS from Eells, 9-Aug-07
    - h. carbon from Goebel to Nathan Abbott, 22-Nov-07
    - h. carbon from Abbott to Goebel, 25-Nov-07
    - h. carbon from Goebel to Abbott and a copied extract from an unpublished account of the dismissal of Prof. Goebel, 27-Nov-07
    - h. carbon from Abbott to Goebel, 8-Dec-07
    - h. carbon from Goebel, 6-Jan-08
    - h. carbon from Abbott to Goebel, 22-Dec-08
  - Newspaper clippings and holograph notes re Goebel and his dismissal, circa 1905-1908 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- University papers, 1901-1916
  - Organization of Stanford University (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1. Tentative suggestions for an organization of the University for internal administration.
    - 2. Suggestions for detailed plan of organization - academic senate.
    - 3. Organization of the faculty of the Leland Stanford Junior University.
    - 4. Organization of the faculty of the Leland Stanford Junior University - corrected copy.
    - 5. Report of the Organization Committee upon the organization of the faculty.
    - 6. Holograph notes by [Davis] re the organization.
  - Miscellaneous clippings re Stanford activities, the administration and the faculty. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Board of Trustees - Reports and Minutes (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 1. Report on Customs as to use of Liquor in Stanford University.
    - 2. Report of committee on Statements of facts and conclusions regarding the riotous proceedings in April 1908.
    - 3. Special report on Power House Location and Operation.
    - 4. Recommendations of the Special Court upon the reports of the President of the University for 1903 - 1904.
    - 5. Resolutions recommended by the Rules Committee, 30-Jul-07
    - 6. Address to the Board of Trustees of Stanford University by Mrs. Jane L. Stanford, President of the Board.
  - Alumni Association (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - TLS from Crothers, 8-May-08
    - Carbon from Crothers to F.V.T. Lee, 8-May-08
    - TLS from F.V.T. Lee, 12-May-08
    - TLS from Lee to Jordan, 12-May-08
    - Carbon typescript of Report of Committee of Constitutional Amendments to the Pres. and Officers of the Alumni Association (Lee, F.J. Teggart and Mr. Wright), 12-May-08
    - Carbon from Lee to Jordan with copy of the Constitution of the Alumni Association, 13-May-08
    - Carbon from Jordan to Lee, 14-May-08
    - TLS from Crothers to Davis, 6-Jul-08
    - TL from Board of Directors of the Stanford Club to Stanford Club members., 31-Jul-08
  - Alumni Representation on Board of Trustees (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - TLS from Jordan with carbon typescript of Yale Method of alumni representation, 21-Dec-05
    - TL from Jerome D. Greene to Jordan, 5-Jul-06
    - TLS from Jordan, 11-Jul-06
    - TL no sig. to Jordan, 19-Jul-06
  - Board (of Trustees) Vacancy (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Extracts from by-laws
    - ALS from Vanderlyn Stow, 2-Sep-08
    - TLS from S.F. Leib, 25-Sep-08
    - TLS from Charles G. Lathrop, 25-Sep-08
    - TLS from H.P. Goodman and [Geo. E. Goodman], 2-Oct-08
    - ALS from Geo. E. Gray, 10-Oct-08
  - Budget, January 1908 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - TLS from H.W. Beebe, 10-Jul-07
    - Carbon from Crothers to Leon Sloss, 26-Dec-07